
# Project notes
Dataset contains Sysmon logs exported after running Atomic Red Team tests.

- Set up Windows VM and installed Sysmon
- Cloned Atomic Red Team repo
- Ran tests:
    Invoke-AtomicTest T1486 -TestNumbers 5
    Invoke-AtomicTest T1486 -TestNumbers 8
    Invoke-AtomicTest T1486 -TestNumbers 9
    Invoke-AtomicTest T1486 -TestNumbers 10
- Exported Sysmon logs as XML
- Ingested into Splunk with index: ransomware_detection
- Wrote SPL queries to detect:
    - ransom note files
    - .akira extension files
    - encryption tools running
    - PowerShell commands to drop ransom notes
- Built dashboards in Splunk UI (timechart, tables, bar charts)

To-do:
- Add Atomic tests from T1490 (vssadmin etc.)
- Build real alert rules in Splunk